Guide to the Consumer Reports. Eileen Nic papers, 1985-1993 RL.11786
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Consumer Reports. Eileen Nic papers
1985-1993
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Consumer Reports (Firm)
RL.11786
0.4 Linear Feet
Consumer Reports is a product testing and consumer advocacy nonprofit organization based in Yonkers, N.Y., founded in 1936. Eileen Nic was a consultant to Consumer Reports on health and environmental issues and an advocate for hazardous chemical and pesticide control. The Consumer Reports Eileen Nic papers include Correspondence, project proposals, research reports and other printed materials that relate to air pollution, chemical accidents, environmental policy, hazardous materials and pesticide use and regulation. Organizations and individuals represented in the collection include Ciba-Geigy, Esther Peterson, International Organization of Consumers' Unions (IOCU, later Consumers International) and Union Carbide (relating to the Bhopal chemical accident). Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized alphabetically.
Biographical / Historical
Consumer Reports is a product testing and consumer advocacy nonprofit organization based in Yonkers, N.Y., founded in 1936. Eileen Nic was a consultant to Consumer Reports on health and environmental issues and an advocate for hazardous chemical and pesticide control.
Eileen Nic was born in Phildelphia in 1951. Nic graduated from Temple University and Columbia University (MA, Sociology) and worked with the Philadelphia Department of Health. Nic served as consultant for pollution toxicity, pesticides and hazardous chemicals with the Sierra Club, Natural Resources Defense Council, and Consumers Union. Nic served as the International Organization of Consumers Union (IOCU) representative to the United Nations. Nic died in New York in 1993.
Source: New York Times obituary, June 26, 1993.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Consumer Reports. Eileen Nic papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2019.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
American Association of Advertising Agencies vertical files
Consumer Reports Advocacy records
Consumer Reports Washington Office records
J. Walter Thompson Company. Information Center vertical files
J. Walter Thompson Company. Publications
McCann-Erickson Worldwide vertical files
T.S. Ferree, Jr. papers
Collection Overview
The Consumer Reports Eileen Nic papers include Correspondence, project proposals, research reports and other printed materials that relate to air pollution, chemical accidents, environmental policy, hazardous materials and pesticide use and regulation. Organizations and individuals represented in the collection include Ciba-Geigy, Esther Peterson, International Organization of Consumers' Unions (IOCU, later Consumers International) and Union Carbide (relating to the Bhopal chemical accident). Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Consumer advocacy; consumer protection; Pesticides -- Health aspects -- United States; Pollution; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Nic, Eileen
- Professional Files, 1985-1993; 1
  - Banned substances exports, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Chemical accident project proposal, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Ciba-Geigy Summit, 1985-1987 (Box 1)
  - Citizen's Commission on Bhopal, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Discussion paper on U.N. Harmful Substance Resolution, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Environmental Policy Committee, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Esther Peterson correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 1)
  - IOCU (International Organization of Consumer Unions), 1991 (Box 1)
  - Obituary, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Prior Informed Consent in the International Code of Conduct on Use and Distribution of Pesticides (Pesticides Trust), 1989 (Box 1)
  - The First Three Years: Implementing the World Bank Pesticide Guidelines 1985-1988 (Michael Hansen) (Box 1)
  - Toxic Air Pollution from New York City Industry (Eileen Nic and Beth Inabinett), 1990 (Box 1)
  - Toxic Chemical Accident Risks in New York City (Barbara Warren and Eileen Nic), 1991 (Box 1)
  - Unregistered pesticides hearing, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Violating the Code: A Preliminary Survey of Indonesia, the Philippines and Thailand (Michael Hansen, Sarojini Rengam), 1987 (Box 1)
  - YMCA Youth Leadership Institute award, 1986 (Box 1)